# RUCHIKA

# **GRAPHIC DESIGN SPECIALIST**



+91 8688984809

cruchika263@gmail.com

Greater Faridabad, Delhi NCR, 121003

I am a passionate and dedicated individual with a keen interest in Marketing, Promotion and Communication. Completed my Bachelors of Designing in Fashion Promotion and Communication at NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF FASHION TECHNOLOGY (HYDERABAD). I am looking towards a career in the creative communications industry, specialising in business development, merchandising, marketing, retail management and brand communication where I will be able to learn more about my field of action and utilising the knowledge for further betterment in my work.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Photoshop/Illustrator/After Effects/Indesign/Corel Draw

## **EDUCATION**

Diploma in Fashion
Designing
Govt. Polytechnic for women,
Faridabad
2013 - 2015

Bachelors of Designing
National Institute of Fashion
Technology, Fashion
Communication, Hyderabad
2015-2019

# **PORTFOLIO**

https://www.behance.net/cruchika26114b

# **PROFESSIONAL PROFILE**

Graphic Design Specialist with 3 years of experience in the management of the complete design process, from conceptualisation to delivery. Expert at interdepartmental coordination and communication. Skilled with Adobe Creative Suite (Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign), Microsoft Office Suite, and Video design applications (After Effects, Premier Pro). Able to stretch the boundaries of web design and digital storytelling to help my client's brands stand out.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **GRAPHIC DESIGN SPECIALIST**

Aakarist Design India Ltd. (April 2019-October 2019)

- Developed numerous marketing programs (logos, brochures, newsletters, infographics, presentations, and advertisements).
- Managed up to 2 projects at a given time while under pressure to meet weekly deadlines.
- Recommended and consulted with clients on the most appropriate graphic design options based on their overall marketing goals.

# **GRAPHIC DESIGN SPECIALIST**

Trends Institute of Fashion Technology, Hyderabad (Jan 2020-Sep 2020))

- Lead in the design, development, and implementation of the graphic, layout, and production communication materials.
- Trained students with skills and softwares like After effects, Photography, Fashion Styling, Graphic Designing.
- Delegate tasks to the 7 members of the design team and provide counsel on all aspects of the project.

### SENIOR GRAPHIC DESIGN SPECIALIST

Abode Biotec India Pvt. Ltd., Hyderabad (Jan 2021-October 2022)

- Created a high volume of layout, graphic and production design.
- Created wireframes and page designs for multiple client websites.
- Supervise the assessment of all graphic materials in order to ensure quality and accuracy of the design.